Navid Mohseni

Data Analyst / Statistician

(+98)9126172697

navvidmohseni@gmail.com

www.navidmohseni.ir

Tehran

I am enthusiastic about data science, statistical modeling, machine learning, and data visualization. My research interest is to combine statistics and machine learning to overcome health, environmental, financial, or any major problem we have faced today. I enjoy working in a collaborative environment with people from various backgrounds to enhance my knowledge and understanding of real-world data. Find more about me on my website.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Biostatistics

Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences | 2017 - 2020

- Thesis title: A cure rate survival model with hyper-Poisson frailty distribution for relapsed or refractory Hodgkin lymphoma patients after stem cell transplantation.
- GPA: 16.82 (Out of 20)

Bachelor of Science in Statistics

Shahid Beheshti University | 2011 - 2015

- A four-year degree where I've studied courses such as Regression, Design of Experiment, Survival Analysis, Reliability, Probability, Time Series Analysis, Nonparametric Statistics, Multivariate Analysis, Experimental Design
- GPA: 13.62 (Out of 20)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Data Analyst

Mar. 2019 - Present

- Analyze data sets from clients to create clear and compelling reports, visualizations, and interactive apps.
- Communicate and share the results of the analyses for better decision making.

Data Analyst

TezolMarket | May 2017 - Mar. 2019

- Generated statistical reports to support business strategy, and visualized the results for better decision making.
- Predictive analysis and associated processes, including pre-processing and cleaning data, exploratory data analysis, model training, testing, and evaluation.

Statistician and R&D

Rahkar-Andishan | Oct. 2016 - May 2017

- Worked in R&D, advertising strategies, and analyzed the business development.
- Analyzed and enhanced the performance and reliability of our web services by analyzing the data.

SKILLS

Advanced

R

PostgreSQL / MySQL

Tableau

R-Markdown

SPSS

Rusty bits of

Python

Google Analytics

HONORS AND AWARDS

Ranked 10th of Nationwide

Master Entrance exam in

Biostatistics out of 2000

participant - August 2017

Ranked in top 0.5% among more than 250,000 participants in Nationwide entrance exam for an undergraduate degree - 2011

Second place in Photography awards competition of Shahid Beheshti University – May 2012

Intern Statistician

Shahab-Yab | Jun. 2016 - Sept. 2016

Monthly statistical reports and analyzing business development.

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Articles

- A cure rate survival model after stem cell transplantation for relapsed or refractory Hodgkin lymphoma patients. Mohseni N, Khadem Maboudi A, Baghestani A, Saeedi A. Middle east journal of cancer (under review).
- The Optimal Cut-off Score of the Nijmegen Questionnaire for Diagnosing Hyperventilation Syndrome Using a Bayesian Model in the Absence of a Gold Standard. Azizmohommad Looha M, Masaebi F, Mohseni N, Abedi M, Fakharian F. Galen Medical Journal.
- The Predictive Value of Serum Cytokines for Distinguishing Celiac Disease from Non-Celiac Gluten Sensitivity and Healthy Subjects. Masaebi F, Azizmohmmad Looha M, Rostami-nejad M, Pourhoseingholi M, Mohseni N, Samasca G, Lupan I, Rezaie M, Zali M. Iranian Biomedical Journal.
- The prediction of Mortality Incidence in Patients with CKD based on influential prognostic Factors with Competing Risks Approach. Saeedi A, Baghestani A, Hashemi S, Maboudi A, Minoo F, Mohseni N, Esfahani Z. Galen Medical Journal.
- A cure rate model with discrete frailty on Hodgkin lymphoma patients after diagnosis.
 Mohseni N, Khadem Maboudi A, Baghestani A, Saeedi A. Mohseni N, Khadem Maboudi A, Baghestani A, Saeedi A. Archives of Advances in Biosciences (under review).
- Assessing the diagnostic power of Cystatin C and Creatinine in the detection of chronic kidney disease. Masaebi F, Azizmohmmad Looha M, Mohseni N, Nasiri M, Kazerouni F, Zayeri F. DOI: 10.22037/aab. v10i3.25589.

CONDUCTING WORKSHOPS AND TEACHING

Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences

•	Workshop: Data Visualization with ggplot2 in R (Online)	Sept. 2020
•	Workshop: Data Transformation with dplyr in R (Online)	May 2020
•	Workshop: SQL fundamentals	Apr. 2020
•	Workshop: Intermediate R	Nov. 2018
•	Workshop: Basics with R	Oct. 2018
•	Teaching Assistant of Statistical Methods III course Under the supervision of Dr. Zayeri	Fall 2019
•	Teaching Assistant of Biostatistics (for epidemiology students) course Under the supervision of Dr. Khodakarim	Fall 2018
•	Teaching Assistant of Probability I course Under the supervision of Dr. Faghihi	Fall 2015

Assistant Editor of the Journal of Statistics for Department of Statistics – 2013

Champion of Futsal competition (mathematics and statistics department's team) of Shahid Beheshti University – 2014

LANGUAGES

Persian: Native

English: Professional

Dutch: Familiar

ACADEMIC REFEREES

Dr. Khadem Maboudi

Associate Professor, Dept. Biostatistics of Shahid Beheshti University of medical sciences amaboudi@sbmu.ac.ir

Dr. Zayeri

Associate Professor, Dept. Biostatistics of Shahid Beheshti University of medical sciences fzayeri@yahoo.com

Dr. Alavi Majd

Professor, Dept. Biostatistics of Shahid Beheshti
University of medical sciences
alavimajd@sbmu.ac.ir
alavimajd@gmail.com